<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Castlerock</title>
    <link>http://www.castlerock.se/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Castlerock</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 12:04:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.castlerock.se/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>wallrite</title>
      <link>http://www.castlerock.se/project/wallrite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 12:04:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.castlerock.se/project/wallrite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In April 2015 I started working on a system for large, interactive,
distributed whiteboards together with
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wallrite.se&#34;&gt;Wallrite Scandinavia&lt;/a&gt;. We founded a separate
company, &lt;a href=&#34;http://wallrite.eu&#34;&gt;Wallrite Interactive&lt;/a&gt;, in which
development is now ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>misc</title>
      <link>http://www.castlerock.se/quote/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 21:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.castlerock.se/quote/misc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a weakness in the people&amp;hellip; I can feel it.
    &amp;ndash; Elizabeth, The Americans&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rpi 2 bitcoin full node</title>
      <link>http://www.castlerock.se/post/rpi-2-bitcoin-full-node/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 20:09:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.castlerock.se/post/rpi-2-bitcoin-full-node/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I admit, I was a bit late in the game regarding Bitcoin. Or more
than a little actually. Sure, I&amp;rsquo;ve read a bit about it, but I never
really got into it. Until a few months ago, when I had lunch with a
former colleague who is very much into Bitcoin. We met up for lunch at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://epicenterstockholm.com/&#34;&gt;Epicenter&lt;/a&gt;. I had a sandwich,
minderal water, and I tried out the first Bitcoin
&lt;a href=&#34;http://coinatmradar.com/bitcoin_atm/434/bitcoin-atm-bitaccess-stockholm-btcx-office/&#34;&gt;ATM&lt;/a&gt;
in Stockholm. Since then I have been spending a lot of time reading up
on Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;ve decided I must try to setup my own full Bitcoin node. It
seems like good fun, and also the adult, responsible thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to go pretty minimal, while still being reasonably simple to
setup. So I opted for a Raspberry Pi 2 with
&lt;a href=&#34;http://archlinuxarm.org/platforms/armv7/broadcom/raspberry-pi-2&#34;&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I started out, I thought that I would be able to make the world a
wonderful service by documenting my endeavor. Turns out I only had to
follow the instructions for installing
&lt;a href=&#34;http://archlinuxarm.org/platforms/armv7/broadcom/raspberry-pi-2&#34;&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt;,
installing bitcoind and bitcoin-cli from packages, and then following
the instructions at &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitcoin.org/en/full-node&#34;&gt;bitcoin.org&lt;/a&gt;
for setting up a full node (granted, I should probably have built from
source myself, to be on the safe side). It&amp;rsquo;s not the fastest node in
the network, but hey, it&amp;rsquo;s cheap and simple, and thus far looks like a
great way to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have not yet opened up my node for incoming traffic, as I am waiting
for the blockchain to synchronize.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lfe</title>
      <link>http://www.castlerock.se/page/lfe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 12:42:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.castlerock.se/page/lfe/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A LISP running on the BEAM, how extraordinary! This must certainly
represent the tip of human evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been following &lt;a href=&#34;http://lfe.io&#34;&gt;lfe&lt;/a&gt; at a distance almost from
the start, but I have never actually done anything with it. Time to
change that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My starting point was to install lfe on one of my Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s. I
started out installing
&lt;a href=&#34;http://archlinuxarm.org/platforms/armv7/broadcom/raspberry-pi-2&#34;&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt;. I
then installed Erlang/OTP 18 using pacman. After this I could simply
compile lfe from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rvirding/lfe&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;. This gives
me the following REPL:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;mjl@galadriel:~ $ lfe
Erlang/OTP 18 [erts-7.0] [source] [smp:4:4] [async-threads:10] [hipe] [kernel-poll:false]

LFE Shell V7.0 (abort with ^G)
&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have only just begun playing with lfe, and I intend to continue to
add my findings and impressions to this page as I go, so please come
back and visit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;left-fold-aka-foldl-aka-reduce:048fc8b676dece52fabaec864166e226&#34;&gt;left fold aka foldl aka reduce&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; (lists:foldl (lambda (n acc) (+ n acc)) 0 &#39;(1 2 3 4 5 6))
21
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://www.castlerock.se/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.castlerock.se/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My name is &lt;a href=&#34;https://se.linkedin.com/in/liseborn&#34;&gt;Johan Liseborn&lt;/a&gt; and I
have been working with software development since 1989, when I joined
Ericsson in Bollmora. After a few years of developing PBXes in
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PLEX_(programming_language)&#34;&gt;Plex-M&lt;/a&gt;
I went to study computer science in
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.liu.se/utbildning/pabyggnad/6MICS?l=en&#34;&gt;Linköping&lt;/a&gt;. During
that time, the internet became a thing, and since then, most of what I
have been working on has been internet related.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1999 I co-founded Hotsip, where we built voice, video, and chat
applications and infrastructure based on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc3261.txt&#34;&gt;SIP&lt;/a&gt;. Hotsip got acquired by
Oracle in 2006, and I spent a few years there. After that I co-founded
a company offering mobile based task management for small businesses,
but that never took off. I spent a few years working in the financial
industry, first with TriOptima, and then briefly with Klarna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2010 I joined Glactic to work on a web based dating service
including real-time voice and video speed dating. The system was
pretty cool, including a real-time matching engine based on Solr, and
a real-time voice and video exchange engine built in Erlang, but once
again, the service never took off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late 2011 I became employee #1 and CTO at Magine TV, where I was
part of designing and building, from the ground, a real-time
transcoding and streaming system for live, linear TV. I left Magine at
the beginning of 2015, to found Castlerock and work on new, exciting
projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the years I have learned that I like startups, and I like to
be part of solving new problems and creating new systems from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the years, I have been working with many different things,
from being a junior programmer to being a manager, a CTO, a board
member, and a chairman of the board. I have found that what I like
most is to work in startups, with a bright team, solving new problems,
and building systems from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think that there is something I could help out with, please do
not hesitate to drop me a &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@castlerock.se&#34;&gt;mail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;my-history-in-computing:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;my history in computing&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started out learning programming on my own in the early 80s. The
first computer I used was a friends
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ZX81&#34;&gt;ZX81&lt;/a&gt;. I then got a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commodore_VIC-20&#34;&gt;VIC-20&lt;/a&gt;, followed by
a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commodore_64&#34;&gt;C64&lt;/a&gt;. I started out
programming in Basic on the ZX81 and the two Commodore machines. I
also started learning 6502 assembler on the VIC-20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &amp;lsquo;84 or &amp;lsquo;85 I got a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sinclair_QL&#34;&gt;Sinclair QL&lt;/a&gt;, which was a
really cool machine. It had a basic interpreter that was really easy,
to extend with your own commands (in assembler), and it had a 68008
CPU, which meant I could start playing around with 68k assembly. It
also had a pretty neat storage system, consisting of two &amp;ldquo;microdrives&amp;rdquo;
with infinite loop tape cartridges. The only thing that sucked was the
graphics, so it was no-good for gaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &amp;lsquo;86 or &amp;lsquo;87 I got an
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atari_ST&#34;&gt;Atari 1040ST&lt;/a&gt;, and a few
years later I had a brief stint with an
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atari_ST#Atari_TT&#34;&gt;Atari TT&lt;/a&gt;. Sometime
in the mid 80s, I don&amp;rsquo;t remember exactly when, I read an interview
with Richard M. Stallman in a Swedish computer magazine. This was my
first real exposure to free software. I found out that there was quite
a lot of free software available for the Atari, and I started
downloading and playing with all kinds of different free software
packages, including Lisp and Scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime during &amp;lsquo;89 or &amp;lsquo;90 I got my first Sun workstation at work
(this was at Ericsson; before that it had all been IBM mainframes at
work), and I started learning Unix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got my first regular PC, a 486, sometime in the early 90s, probably
in &amp;lsquo;92. I ran windows for a while, I tried OS/2 (it was handed out for
free at my university and it was completely useless on that machine),
and then switched to GNU/Linux, probably late &amp;lsquo;92 or early &amp;lsquo;93.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In December &amp;lsquo;99 I got hold of &lt;a href=&#34;http://openbsd.org&#34;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt; 2.6 and
fell in love with the OS and the approach of the project. The focus,
the attention to detail, and the dedication to the project goals, as
well as the somewhat brusk, no-nonse and to-the-point way of
communication (that some people perceive as rude) are all things I
appreciate. For a few years, I ran OpenBSD as my primary operating
system, on a number of IBM ThinkPads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the mid 90s I have had a whole bunch of machines, mostly
laptops, and mostly IBM ThinkPads (and later Lenovos). I switched to
Apple machines (I know, I know) sometime in the mid 00s, the first one
was a 12&amp;rdquo; PowerBook. I have always been fond of small laptops,
favoring portability rather than raw performance. This also goes well
with my thought that most software is bloated, and that we in general
should be able to get by with smaller, cheaper machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been pretty happy with OS X for many years, but I am not too
fond of its non-freeness, and it&amp;rsquo;s increasing focus on locking the
users in and seducing them into buying stuff, so recently I have
started to switch over to run GNU/Linux on most of my lingering Apple
machines. Currently, my main laptop is a mid-2012 MacBook Air running
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxmint.com/&#34;&gt;Linux Mint 17.2 Rafaela Cinnamon Edition&lt;/a&gt;. The
use of GNU/Linux is mostly out of laciness, and my current goal is to
switch back to using OpenBSD as my main operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>